they knew these fires were coming and
we're going to give you the Smoking Gun
fortunately in the public sector
everything is public
and the city of Los Angeles spent a lot
of money back in
20121 in order to assess the risk of
fire danger in LA county and what this
document here uh discusses and really
it's it's public information I'm going
to put it on my bio it's also going to
be on my YouTube channel Wy sprocket you
can view this um resilient ca.org which
is a case St sponsored by the city of
Los Angeles on the risks of fire danger
and what they needed to do and what
their priorities are and you'll be blown
away to know that it had very little to
do with prevention and everything to do
with diversity equity and inclusion and
I know that's a word that's getting
thrown around a lot
but when you see it in
writing and when you see that fires no
nothing about race know nothing about
income they know nothing the Fire
doesn't know any of that and so why
the LA County would focus on this is
just crazy to me because you know when
you look at the par when you look at the
paradise fou the Santa Rosa fire the
Malibu fire the San Diego fire and now
the LA fire since 20 from since 2000
till today LA California will have over
$500 billion dollar in fire damage
compare that to Florida which is about
200 billion with the Hurricanes which
are can be far more destructive because
it's a it's a wider area fires are
isolated so $500 billion a half a
trillion dollars is a lot of money and
the elephant in the room throughout the
entire country is we all saw this coming
it's not a surprise nobody is surprised
or shocked because the writing was on
the wall and you know when when Paradise
burned down you know people were kind of
like oh that really kind of sucks even
though you know it was 153,000 Acres
18,000 structures burned and then you
had the Santa you know the Santa Rosa
burned down and everyone was like okay
this is kind of getting crazy and now
this and that doesn't again count Malibu
and San die and the San Diego fire so
when you look at this document uh which
is the LA County uh climate
vulnerability assessment it goes into
all of the risk issues including the
extreme heat the Wildfire danger Inland
flooding Coastal they look at all of
that but the biggest thing as you go
through this
150 uh page document is it talks a lot
about the poor it highlights systemic
inequalities focusing on disadvantaged
groups such as lowincome household
racial minorities and people with
disabilities as the primary targets of
the risk did this fire know any of those
groups I I don't know I it doesn't seem
like it um the report outlines projected
risks such as increase in Wildfire
frequency and intensity yet there is
limited
limited acable Solutions on what they're
going to do about it in my personal
opinion the state of California wants to
bring the state of California back to
the
1900s because the state officials that
removing dams um I wouldn't be surprised
if the state of California
purchases all of the land around uh the
the burnt areas around the coast around
the Palisades they're going to purse I
wouldn't be surprised if they donated
the land back to the Native Americans
which maybe rightfully so because this
is what the report talks about in terms
of the inequality of um of the community
so the conclusion the conclusion on this
report if you look right here is the
general plan updates offer a great
opportunity for municipalities to
prioritize Equitable climate action
that's one the county recognizes the
ways in which past policies have
perpetuated Injustice and how those
injustices contributed to climate
vulnerability experienced today and
they're going to prioritize historically
disadvantaged people and mitigate
greenhouse gases so basically it's about
race it's not about actually doing the
things necessary to mitigate fire danger
um and when you look at the again past
history is a indication of future
results $500
billion in damage
since 2 500 that's a lot of money it's
more than any other state it's double
the amount of Damages than the
hurricanes have experienced in Florida
and all of it could be preventable it
could have been prevented had the state
officials prioritize physical actionable
items when the fires happen in Oregon to
to basically spend a lot of money to
mitigate removing large swats of trees
from highways like High High 97 in
clearing those highways so if there was
ever a fire again they could contain it
really quickly California doesn't seem
to be doing that so anyway check out the
report let me know in the comments below